LOGISTICS ANALYST - OUTBOUND

Dollar Tree Stores Chesapeake, VA Full-Time

Create Job Alert.

Get similar jobs sent to your email

Logistics Analyst

Outbound

* Complete daily routing process to accomplish excellent on-time delivery service to the stores at the lowest possible cost. Includes creating truck routes, delivery appt schedules, maintaining computer models, distribution center grid (wave optimization), and control reports.
* Monitor the execution of the daily routing by the distribution center and dedicated carrier. Follow-up with the timing of loading completion and on-time carrier pickup.
* Coordinate the execution of the delivery plan by the dedicated carrier. Includes updating stores, distribution center, and outbound transportation manager on all service deviations.
* Facilitate effective communication between the dedicated carrier, outbound transportation, the distribution center, and the stores. Provide customer service support to the stores on all transportation and distribution issues.
* Monitor distribution center trailer pool to allow an adequate number of trailers to complete loading schedules.
* Optimize backhaul execution of Dollar Tree inbound shipments and revenue share loads with the dedicated carrier.
* Complete other analysis, reporting, projects and duties as assigned by the Transportation management team.

Transportation Planning

* Develop / design reports and reporting mechanisms to monitor and control all aspects of the supply chain, including vendors, merchants, carriers, and distribution centers.
* Facilitate effective communication between the vendors, merchants, and Transportation to report logistics cost, service standards, and transport plan throughout the supply chain.
* Monitor data/information flows between transportation/mainframe systems and departments.
* Provide customer service support to the entire company to meet each transportation departments delivery and service requirements.
* Complete other analysis, reporting, projects, system administration functions and duties as assigned by the Transportation management team.

Minimum Requirements/Qualifications:

* Bachelors Degree or equivalent work experience (at least 4 years of logistics work experience for non-bachelor degree holders).
* Proficiency in MS Excel, MS Word, and MS Powerpoint.
* Demonstrated understanding of basic principles of Logistics and Distribution
* Group or individual project work that demonstrated problem solving and analytical strength or comparable experience in the work force.
* Ability to effectively communicate, both verbally and in writing, logistics procedures within the department and outside of the department.
* Must be capable of using operational support software to complete daily tasks.

Desired Qualifications :

* MS Access query building and database creation
* Capable of writing visual basic code and macros in MS Excel/Acces

Recommended skills

Microsoft Power Point

Scheduling

Microsoft Access

Microsoft Word

Microsoft Excel

Complex Problem Solving
